Eunkyoung (Kyoung) Choi

Email: kyoung.choi@colostate.edu || Personal Website: https://kyoungyi.github.io

PERSONAL PROFILE

Highly motivated to become a climate risk scientist who helps the interface of physical and social sciences by understanding both fields. Particularly interested in helping vulnerable communities around the world by improving the understanding on the impact of climate change on agricultural production from both scientific and economic perspectives. Excellent capacity to understand new concepts, quickly acclimate to different situations, and substantively contribute to various fields of earth science, green growth policy research and environmental consulting over the past 4 years.

RESEARCH INTERESTS: climate risk, agricultural production, statistical models, machine learning

EDUCATION

Colorado State University

August 2020 - Present

- Ecosystem Science and Sustainability
- Advisor: Professor Nathan Mueller

University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, IL, United States

September 2018 – May 2020

- MS: Atmospheric Sciences
- Master's Thesis Title: Modeling the Combined Environmental Effects on Net Land Carbon Flux in the Present and Future Scenarios
- Advisor: Professor Atul Jain

Pukyong National University, Busan, Korea

March 2008-August 2014

- BE: Ecological Engineering and International Business Administration
- Bachelor's Thesis Title: Emergy Accounting for Korea in 2011

Northern Virginia Community College, Alexandria, VA

January 2012-May 2012

• International Exchange Program

EXPERIENCE

| AN ENDINCE | | | | |
|--|---------------------------|--|--|--|
| Colorado State University | Fort Collins CO, The U.S. | | | |
| Research Assistant, Ecosystem Science and Sustainability | August 2020 – Present | | | |
| University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign | Champaign IL, The U.S. | | | |
| Research Assistant, Atmospheric Sciences Department | September 2018 – May 2020 | | | |
| Environmental Resources Management | Seoul, South Korea | | | |
| Environmental Consultant | March 2014-March 2017 | | | |
| | | | | |
| Global Green Growth Institute | Seoul, South Korea | | | |
| Research Intern, India Team | July 2013-August 2013 | | | |
| U.SKorea Institute, Johns Hopkins School of Advanced International Studies | Washington D.C., The U.S. | | | |
| Research Intern, Energy, Resources and Environment | February 2013-May 2013 | | | |
| NASA Goddard Space Flight Center | Greenbelt MD, The U.S. | | | |
| Research Intern, Earth Sciences Division | May 2012-January 2013 | | | |
| Research Intern, Earth Sciences Division | 1v1ay 2012-January 2013 | | | |

PUBLICATIONS

- Driscoll, A.W., Conant, R.T., Marston, L.T., **Choi, E.**, & Mueller, N. (2024) Greenhouse gas emissions from US irrigation pumping and implications for climate-smart irrigation policy. Nat Commun 15, 675. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-024-44920-0
- Choi, E., Rigden, A. J., Tangdamrongsub, N., Jasinski, M. F., & Mueller, N. (2023). US crop yield losses from hydroclimatic hazards. Environmental Research Letters, 19(1), 014005. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/ad0c87

Eunkyoung (Kyoung) Choi

Email: kyoung.choi@colostate.edu || Personal Website: https://kyoungyi.github.io

Driscoll, A. W., Leuthold, S. J., Choi, E., Clark, S. M., Cleveland, D. M., Dixon, M., Hsieh, M., Sitterson, J., & Mueller, N. (2022). Divergent impacts of crop diversity on caloric and economic yield stability. Environmental Research Letters, 17(12), 124015. https://doi.org/10.1088/1748-9326/aca2be

ORAL AND POSTER PRESENTATIONS

- Choi E., & Mueller, N. D., Impacts of geographical shifts in cropland on hydroclimatic hazard exposure, Abstract, American Geophysical Union Fall Meeting, 11-15 December 2023.
- Choi, E., Davenport, F., Dillon, J., & Mueller, N. D., Using explainable machine learning to develop a weather stress index for dairy systems, American Geophysical Union Fall Meeting, 11-15 December 2023.
- Choi, E., Machine learning in climate-agricultural risks and adaptations, Colorado Seed Growers Association and Colorado Seed Industry Association Annual Meeting, 7th December 2023.
- Choi, E., & Mueller, N. D., Inconsistencies in using Existing Thermal Indices for US Milk Yield Sensitivities, American Dairy Science Association Annual Meeting, 24 June 2023.
- Choi, E., & Mueller, N. D., Evaluating Indices for Extreme Weather Stress on US Milk Yields, American Geophysical Union Fall Meeting, 12-16 December 2022.
- Choi, E., Sloat, L., & Mueller, N. D., Sensitivity and Exposure to Hydrologic Hazards for Major US Crops 1981-2016, American Geophysical Union Fall Meeting, 13-17 December 2021.

EXTRACURRICULUM ACTIVITIES

| • | Elected President, Department of Atmospheric Sciences Student Organization at UIUC, United States | 2019 |
|---|---|------|
| • | Elected Vice President, Department of Ecological Engineering Student Council at PNU, Korea | 2016 |

AWARDS

| • | Best Scientific Poster, Environmental Research Virtual Poster Competition, Institute of Physic | s Publishing, |
|---|--|---------------|
| | the UK | 2023 |
| • | Follet Memorial Travel Award, The Department of Soil and Crop Sciences, CSU, The U.S. | 2023 |
| • | Top 10 3 Minutes Thesis Contest, American Dairy Science Association, The U.S. | 2023 |
| • | ERM Global Recognition Award, Environmental Resources Management, Korea | 2016 |
| • | WEST Program (ROK/US Joint Government Scholarship, The Korean government, Korea | 2012-2013 |
| • | CBA International Business by Pukyung National University, Korea | 2011 |
| • | Idea Contest for Low Carbon Green Growth, Pukyung National University, Korea | 2010 |
| • | Korean Government University Award, The Korean government, Korea | 2008-2011 |

CERTIFICATES

| • | Graduate Certificate in Data Analysis, the Department of Statistics, CSU, the U.S. | 2021 |
|---|--|------|
| • | Korean National Off-Site Consequence Analysis Consultant | 2015 |
| • | Korean National Technical Qualification for Air Pollution | 2011 |
| | | |

SKILLS

- Computer: Python, Fortran, Linux
- Language: Korean (native speaker), English (fluent speaker)